unicef.org.uk 2016-10-19

# Cookies and privacy | Unicef UK

## 1\. Statement of Intent

From time to time, you will be asked to submit personal information about yourself (e.g. name and email address etc.) in order to receive information, use services on our websites or to carry out a particular action, for example:

  * to receive an e-newsletter
  * to take an online action
  * to make a donation or purchase a product
  * to leave a comment
  * to enter a competition
  * to help you complete a donation or transaction through email

By entering your details in the fields requested, Unicef UK will be able to provide you with the services or carry out the action you select. Whenever you provide such personal information, we will treat that information in accordance with this statement. Our services are designed to give you the information that you want to receive. Unicef will act in accordance with current legislation and aim to meet current internet best practice.

## 2\. **Cookies**

During the course of any visit to our websites, the pages which you see, along with something called a cookie, are downloaded to your computer (see What is a cookie? below for more on this). Most, if not all, websites do this, and that's because cookies allow the website publisher to do useful things like find out whether the computer (and probably its user) has visited the site before. This is done on a repeat visit by checking to see, and finding, the cookie left there on the last visit.

**What is a cookie?**

When you enter a site your computer will automatically be issued with a cookie. Cookies are text files which identify your computer to our server. Cookies in themselves do not identify the individual user, just the computer used. Many sites do this whenever a user visits their site, in order to track traffic flows. Cookies themselves only record which areas of the site have been visited by the computer in question, and for how long. Users have the opportunity to set their computers to accept all cookies, to notify them when a cookie is issued, or not to receive cookies at any time, although this of course means that certain personalised services cannot then be provided to that user. You should read the information that came with your browser software to see how you can do this.  Even assuming you have not set your computer to reject cookies, you can browse our sites anonymously until such time as you register for Unicef services or information.

Further information about cookies can be found at the Interactive Advertising Bureau’s website [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

**What do we use cookies for?**

We use cookies so that we can give you a better experience when you return to our websites.In particular we use cookies to:

  * personalise the sites to your requirements. For example: if on a previous visit you went to, say, the Africa Appeal pages, then we might find this out from your cookie and highlight particular information - which you may find interesting, on a second visit;
  * avoid lengthy registration/personalisation on each visit;
  * identify who you are and to access your account information;
  * estimate our audience size and patterns;
  * display relevant advertising on other websites you visit;
  * ensure that you are not asked to register twice;
  * track preferences and to improve and update our websites; and
  * track the progress and number of entries in some of our promotions and competitions.
  * Download a directory of the cookies used by Unicef UK (PDF).

## 3. **Submitting personal information**

When you supply any personal information to Unicef we have legal obligations towards you in the way we deal with that data. We will always handle your data in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and the Privacy and Electronic Communication Regulations. We have to collect the information fairly, (see the notices on particular web pages which let you know why we are requesting the information) and to let you know how we will use it and whether we will pass the information on to anyone else.

**How do we collect information?**

We obtain personal information from you when you enquire about our activities, register with us, make a donation to us, or otherwise provide us with personal information.

**What information do we collect?**

The personal information we collect might include name, date of birth, email address, postal address, telephone number and credit/debit cards.

We also gather general information about the use of our websites, such as which pages users visit most often and which services or events are of most interest. We may also collect information about how users interact with Unicef UK emails, for example, how many people opened the email and which pages users visit when they click on links in emails. Wherever possible, we use aggregated or anonymous information that does not identify individuals.

## 4\. **How is your information used?**

We will use the information you provide to us to, for example:-

  * to provide you with the services, products or information you have requested, or include you in prize draws or competitions you have entered 
  * process donations or other payments and verify financial transactions
  * process orders, deliver products and communicate with you about orders
  * identify visitors
  * provide a personalised service to you when you visit our websites e.g. by customising the content and/or layout of our pages for each individual user, or sending you a personalised email to help you complete your donation/transaction on our website
  * provide a personalised service to you when you receive our emails and improve our emails to provide you with the best service
  * record any contact we have with you
  * prevent or detect fraud or abuses of our websites and enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions on our behalf
  * to profile use of our websites and carry out research on our users' demographics, interests and behaviour to help us gain a better understanding of how our users navigate and use our websites, and to enable us to improve our service to you
  * provide you with information which we think may be of interest to you, as explained below.

We may use other companies to provide services on our behalf, including packaging, mailing and delivering purchases, answering customers’ questions about products or services, sending postal mail and emails, analysing data and processing credit card payments. We will only provide those companies with the information they need to deliver the service. We may disclose aggregate statistics about our site visitors, customers and sales in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers and other reputable third parties and for other lawful purposes, but these statistics will include no personally identifying information.

One particular service we use is the Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. You can [opt out and configure how your information is used here](http://www.google.com/settings/ads). If you would like to opt out of all Google Analytics tracking services then you can find out about a [browser plugin here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). 

We may share your data with partners, agents or service providers to understand our supporters more effectively and to further our charitable aims. These partners will not use your data to contact or market to you.

We may disclose personal information if required to do so by law or if we believe that such action is necessary to protect and defend the rights, property or personal safety of Unicef UK, our websites or our visitors and for other lawful purposes.

Should we merge with another organisation to form a new entity, your data may be transferred to the new entity.

## 5\. **Direct marketing and user surveys**

As well as using personal information to fulfil requests, we also like to keep our supporters informed about Unicef's activities, campaigns and promotions or about updates to our sites. As Unicef's services expand, there will be more opportunities to enhance the services provided to you. From time to time we may provide you with details of other Unicef services, products, campaigns and promotions which may be of interest to you and offer you the opportunity to subscribe to them. We may also offer you the opportunity to participate in surveys carried out by Unicef or its agents which help our research into the types of service we offer. Unicef will keep a record of information provided by you.

We do agree from time to time with other like-minded organisations to contact each other's supporters for mutual benefit. We would only provide another organisation with your information in this way if you had not objected to us doing so.  In addition, we sometimes contact our supporters with offers from companies that benefit Unicef and may be of interest. In some cases we work with a company on a promotion to raise funds for Unicef, such as our Unicef credit card, and may pass your information to that company so that they can contact you about the promotion.

When submitting your personal information, you will be given the option not to be included in mailings or other contacts from Unicef or other organisations. If you don’t object to us sending you this information, and later decide that you no longer wish to be contacted, you can let us know by emailing: [supportercare@unicef.org.uk](mailto:helpdesk@unicef.org.uk).

Alternatively, you can let us know your communications preferences by [completing this preferences form](https://www.unicef.org.uk/asp/regions/events/application_new/?event=24F5282C-FFAC-4424-96C2-047BFA40ECCD). 

If we contact you by email, each time you receive a message you will also have the option to decline to receive further information from us.      

## 6\. **Access to and changes to your personal information**

You have the right to request a copy of the personal information which Unicef holds about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. (We charge a fee of £10 for information requests.) Please address requests to the Data Protection Officer (email: [supportercare@unicef.org.uk](mailto:helpdesk@unicef.org.uk)).

The Data Protection Act 1998 applies to our use of personal information submitted via our websites. To find out more about your entitlements under this legislation, visit the Information Commissioner's website: [http://www.informationcommissioner.gov.uk](http://www.informationcommissioner.gov.uk/)

## 7\. **Users under 18**

If you are under 18, please make sure that you obtain your parent/guardian's permission beforehand whenever you provide personal information via our websites. Users without this consent are not allowed to provide us with personal information. Also, if you do use our sites to obtain information about fundraising, campaigning or supporting the work of Unicef, please let an adult know.    

## 8\. **Security**

No data transmission over the internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Unicef UK cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to try to ensure its security both on our systems and while in transit between our systems and the companies who provide us with various services (see How is your information used?).   

## 9\. **Fraudulent online activity**

Unicef endeavours to prevent online fraudulent activity taking place. In order to prevent this activity from happening we have put additional security checks in place on our website. As a result of these checks there are times when we will be unable to process card transactions on the first attempt due to missing or incorrect information. This could include an uncompleted field or missing/incorrect address information. On these occasions we will encourage the cardholder to contact our Supporter Care team in order to complete the transaction or to try again online using a different card. If you would like to speak to someone about a transaction you have made please contact our Supporter Care on 0300 330 5580 between 8:00am – 6:00pm from Monday to Friday, or you can email them at [supportercare@unicef.org.uk](mailto:helpdesk@unicef.org.uk).

## 10\. **Links**

Our sites contain links to other sites. We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other websites even if you access them using links from our websites and recommend that you check the policy of each site you visit.

In addition, if you linked to our websites from a third party website, we cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of the owners or operators of that third party site and recommend that you check the policy of that third party site and contact its owner or operator if you have any concerns or questions.      

## 11\. **Where is your information stored?**

Information which you submit via our websites is sent to a computer located in the United Kingdom or elsewhere in the European Economic Area (EEA). This is necessary in order to process the information and to send you the information you have requested. Information submitted by you may be transferred by us to our other offices and to other reputable third party organisations as referred to in this statement, and these may be situated outside the EEA.      

## 12\. **Changes**

We may make changes to this statement from time to time. If we change our Privacy Statement we will post the changes on this page. The amended Privacy Statement will apply from the date it is posted on our site and will govern the way in which we collect and use personal information from the date of the change.

## **Your acceptance of this statement**

By using our sites, you consent to the collection and use of information by Unicef in accordance with this statement. If you do not agree to this statement, please do not use our sites.

This Statement was last updated December 2015.
